How much you give me to eat
this whole jar of olives?
이 올리브 다 먹고
싶은데 얼만큼 줄래?
별로 줄 생각은 없지만
2달러 95센트만 줘
I won't give you anything,
but you'll owe me $2.95.
그러자
Done.
세계 지도 좀 줘
I need an atlas!
Why? Do you have a report due?
왜? 논문이라도 써?
I have a date
with diplomat I met...
UN 밖에서 무료 마사지를
하다가 한 외교관을 만났어
...while I was giving free massages
outside the U. N.
And I don't know where his country is.
근데 어디 사람인지 모르겠어
Let's start with
the free massages at the U.N.
UN에서 무료 마사지를 해?
이 행사의 취지는
'평화를 만드는 육체'야
It's my new thing. I figure,
"Bodies at peace make peace."
마사지 부문에서
노벨 평화상 받겠다
You might just get
the first Nobel Prize in rubbing.
아무튼 어디 사람이라구?
So what country is this guy from?
이히넥... 트리아니스탄
There's a "g" in there.
'g'자가 있었어
Where's that?
그게 어딨는데?
In your atlas!
지도책에!
I don't have an atlas.
지도는 없어
But wait, I do have a globe.
Hold on.
참, 지구본 있다
기다려
어떤 사람인지 말해봐
So what's this guy like?
아주 당당하고...
Well, he's very...
...dashing, you know?
아주 세련됐어
And very, very sophisticated.
영어는 한 마디도 못하는데
통역관 말이, 나한테 빠졌대
And he doesn't speak English...
... but his translator says
he totally gets me.
Okay, here you go.
여기 가져왔어
What is this?
이게 뭐야?
It's a globe.
지구본
And a pencil sharpener.
연필 깎기 겸용
누구 복사할 거 없니?
복사하러 가거든
Need anything copied?
I'm going to the Xerox place.
아니, 없어
No, thanks.
제발 복사 좀 하고 살아
Just give me anything
I can make two of.
If you have nothing to copy,
why go there?
복사 할 것도 없는데
거긴 뭐 하러 가?
또 배꼽찌 한 아가씨 보러
가는 거지?
Are you just gonna gawk
at that girl...
...with the bellybutton ring again?
You wanna come?
응, 너도 갈래?
좋아
The One Where
Ross and Rachel Take a Break
제발, 클로이가
먼저 끝나야 되는데
Come on, Chloe. Finish with
your customer first.
제발, 클로이, 제발!
Come on, Chloe.
Come on, Chloe!
복사하시게요?
Can I help you?
우리 복사물에 대해서
심사숙고해야겠어요
We're having second thoughts
about our copying needs.
생각할 시간을 줘요
And we'll need more time
to think about it.
클로이, 나랑 교대해
이분들이 너한테 반했대
Chloe, switch with me. Some guys
have a crush on you.
저렇게 일러버리냐
Okay, that hurt us.
안녕하세요?
오늘만 두 번째네요
Hi, guys. I haven't seen you
since this morning.
그게...
Well...
알죠?
...you know.
내일 밤 어때요?
What are you doing tomorrow?
우리 둘이요?
Both of us?
Maybe. Does that scare you?
네, 겁나요?
안심해요, 아이작이
필리에서 디제이를 해요
Relax. Isaac's deejaying
at The Philly.
-You should come.
-We'll be there.
- 한번 오세요
- 갈게요
좋아요, 그럼 거기서 봐요
Great. I'll see you then.
좋아요, 또 봄세!
All right! Rock on.
당신과 함께 있으니 낯선 곳이
고향 같다고 하십니다
He says that walking with you makes
this strange city feel like home.
Me too. Although this city
is my home.
저두요, 물론 제 고향은
여기지만... 바보 같죠?
So that's dumb, what I said.
Don't tell him I said that.
이건 통역하지 마세요
다른 말로 해주세요
You make something up.
뭔지 몰라도, 고마워요
Nice! Thank you.
This is me, here.
다 왔어요
눈이 예쁘답니다
Your eyes are very pretty.
Thank you very much.
고마워요...
Oh, thank you.
고마워요
He would like to kiss you.
키스하고 싶답니다
You don't have to do that now.
그런 건 안 하셔도 돼요
No, no, not him!
No, you don't.
아뇨, 키스 말고 통역이요
분위기는 깨졌네요
The moment's over.
There it is, right there.
바로 여기야
정말 작다
It's small.
Yeah, but Sergei said
it took the Germans six weeks...
그래도 게르만족이 거길
지나는데 6주나 걸렸대
...to get all the way across it.
So you had fun?
- 재미는 있니?
- 응
Except for, you know,
when you're on a date...
그런데 그 사람하고
데이트하는 건 좋은데
...and you're getting along great...
통역이 너무 끼어 들어
... but the guy's translator
keeps getting in the way?
싫겠다
- 안녕
레이첼 방에 있어?
Is Rach in her room?
아니, 집에 없어
회사로 전화 해 달래
She's still at work,
but she said to call her.
Is she gonna cancel on me again?
How could she do this?
또 약속 취소야?
이럴 순 없어
What about our anniversary?
오늘 기념일인건 안데?
This is the extent of my knowledge
on the subject.
내가 아는 건 이것 뿐이야
'레이첼에게 전화해'
"Call Rachel."
What's that on the bottom?
밑에 건 뭐야?
무당벌레를 그려봤어
모자도 썼어
That's my doodle of
a ladybug with a top hat.
귀엽지?
She's fancy.
여보세요?
-Hey, honey.
-Oh, hi.
- 안녕, 자기야
- 안녕
What's going on?
또 무슨 일이야?
선적에 문제가 생겨서
이걸 해결해야돼
Shipping had a disaster.
I've gotta get this order in.
너무 미안한데
오늘, 밤새야 될 것 같아
I'm so sorry, but it looks like
I'll be here all night.
What? Well, how about
I come up there?
뭐? 그럼 내가 그리로 갈게
아냐, 그러지 마
일 때문에 꼼짝 못해
No, honey, please.
I just have too much to deal with.
오늘 세르게이를 만나는데
네가 와서 통역관 짝 좀 할래?
Anyway, I'm going out
with Sergei again tonight, and....
Could you be the translator's date...
...so that when we want to be alone...
분위기가 무르익으면
서로 갈라지는 거야
...you two can split off?
통역관도 꽤 생겼어
You know, he's kind of cute.
꽤 생겼다는 건
잘생겼다는 거야?
Like, "really kind of cute"?
아님 스패클백 래리
같다는 거야?
Or "kind of cute" like your friend
Spackle-Back Larry?
그런 투로 말하지마
그 사람 이름이 스패클백 해리야
Don't call him that.
His name is Spackle-Back Harry.
그럼 우리 같이 가자
클로이가 몇 시에 오랬지?
Maybe we should get going.
What time did Chloe say
to get there?
10시 반
-10:30.
-What time is it now?
지금 몇 시야?
4:30.
4시 반
So we'll hang out.
- 그럼 여기서 기다리자
- 그래
그 여자가 셋이 데이트
하자고 한 거 맞지?
Remember when she brought up
that thing about the three of us?
Yes, vividly.
그래, 분명히
그냥 농담이겠지?
-She was kidding about that, right?
-Yeah, I think so.
응, 그럴 거야
당연히 그렇겠지
Yeah, I think so.
실제로 그런 상황이
벌어지면 이상하겠지?
God, it'd be weird if that situation
presented itself tonight.
그렇지...
Yeah, I mean...
...what would we do?
그땐 어떻게 하지?
나라고 알겠냐?
Dude, I don't know.
She was kidding.
- 농담이었겠지
- 응
그렇지...
She was....
그래도 만약을 위해서
기본 원칙을 정해놓자
Just in case, we should have
some ground rules.
그러지 뭐
Yeah. For sure.
우선, 절대 눈뜨지 말자
You probably want the first one to be,
"Never open your eyes."
서로 못 볼걸 보느니
그게 낫지?
Because you don't
want to be doing something...
...and then look up, right?
안 볼 건 안 보는 게 좋잖아
And see something that
you don't want to be seeing.
그게 좋지
Good call. Nice.
Hold it! Hold it!
잠깐만!
눈은 감고 있는데
손이 맘 대로면 어쩌지?
What if my eyes are closed, and...
...and my hand is out there....
Okay, eyes open at all times!
그럼, 그냥 눈뜨자!
그럼 우리 자리는 어떻게...
How do we decide where we...
서로... 알지...
...you know, each would...
...you know...
... be?
자리?
Right. Well, you know,
we could flip for it.
- 알아... 그럼 동전 던지자
- 그래
I guess. But like,
what's heads and what's tails?
그런데 앞면은 뭐고
뒷면은 뭐지?
If you don't know that,
I don't want to do this with you.
그거 안 정하면
너랑 데이트 안 한다
아뇨, 아니에요
구매 주문서가 여기 있는데
No, no. I am looking
at a purchase order here...
각 크기별, 색상별
리비에라 비키니를 주문했네요
...that shows we
ordered the Riviera bikini...
...in a variety of sizes and colors
제 취향이 왜 궁금하시죠?
What does it matter what I'm wearing?
거기 담당자 좀 바꿔주세요
고마워요
Could I speak to your supervisor?
Thank you.
기다리자
Hi.
- 안녕
- 어머, 어떻게 된 거야?
My God!
What are you doing here?
네가 못 온다니까...
Well, you said
you couldn't go out, so....
밤참까지 준비를?
남자친구가 좋긴 좋네
You brought a picnic!
What a boyfriend.
That's it. On Monday, I start
wearing makeup.
월요일부터는
나도 화장한다
자기야, 마음은 고마운데
지금 정신 없어
Honey, this is very nice,
but I've got a crisis.
대신 내가 정신이 있어
But I've got couscous!
미안해,
기념일인 거 알고있어
Honey,
I know it's our anniversary...
... but I told you on the phone,
I don't have time to stop.
아까 전화로 말했듯이
짬이 없어
짬을 낼 필요 없어
난 투명인간이야, 여기 없는 거야
You don't have to stop.
I'm invisible. I'm not here.
그렇지만...
Yeah, but I don't
누가 그랬단 거죠?
Who approved that order?
마크란 사람은 여기 없어요
Well, there is no Mark Robinson
in this office.
마크한테 전화해
-Get Mark on the phone!
-I love Mark. Do you know him?
난 마크 좋더라
마크 아세요?
네!
여기 있는 걸로
확인을 해볼게요
Let me check that
with what I've got.
좋아요, 038은 이 가게
번호가 아니에요
See, 038 is not the number
for this store. 038 is Atlanta.
038은 아틀랜타죠
Pepper?
후추?
- 난 싫어
- 응, 미안...
None for me.
Okay, sorry!
미안해요
Sorry. As I was saying,
the store number is wrong.
가게 번호가 틀렸어요
미안하지만...
And I'm sorry, but
Oh, my God!
세상에!
괜찮아, 괜찮아
죄송하지만
다시 전화 드릴게요
I have to call you back.
I've got Shemp in my office.
비상사태가 발생해서요
이게 무슨 짓이야?
-What are you doing?
-I'm sorry.
정말 미안해...
벌써 전화 끊었어?
와인 한 잔 어때?
But somebody's off the phone!
How about a glass of wine...
불 옆에서!
원하면 다시 피워줄게
... by the fire?
I can get it going again....
아까 내가 한말 잊었어?
조금도 짬이 없다구
You're not listening.
I don't have time to stop.
-You don't have 10 minutes?
-I don't have 10 minutes!
- 레이첼, 단 10분도 안돼?
- 10분도 안돼
-Sophie, does she have 10 minutes?
-I told you, I don't!
- 소피, 정말 10분도 없어요?
- 로스, 정말 왜 이래?
소리 치지마! 최근 들어
오늘이 널 가장 오래 본 거야
Don't yell. This is
the most I've seen you all week.
Look, I cannot do this right now.
I've got a deadline!
지금 싸울 시간 없어
마감 시간 다 됐어
Go home and we'll talk later.
집에 가서, 나중에 얘기해
- 그래, 하지만...
- 잘 가
-Yeah, but wait!
-Goodbye!
그건 우리 건데요
Actually, that's our three-hole punch.
- 왔어?
- 응
Hi.
- 아까 일 말인데...
- 됐어... 다 이해해
Look, about what happened earlier
I completely understand.
You were stressed.
스트레스가 심하지?
나한테 사과할 기회를 줄게
I was gonna give you a chance
to apologize to me.
For letting you throw me
out of your office?
사과?
날 쫓아낸 사람이 누군데?
내가 오라고 부르지 않았어
You had no right
coming down to my office.
You do not bring a picnic basket
to somebody's work...
남의 직장에 음식 바구니
주문한 적도 없구!
... unless they're a park ranger!
도시락 주문이면 모를까!
Excuse me for wanting to be with
my girl on our anniversary.
기념일 좀 챙긴 게
그렇게 큰 죄야?
나만 죽일 놈이군
Boy, what an ass am l!
But I told you
I didn't have the time!
시간 없다고 말했었잖아!
또 그 소리뿐이군
Well, you never have the time.
내가 애인이 있는지도
모를 지경이야
I don't feel like I have
a girlfriend anymore.
Do you want me to quit my job...
나한테 원하는 게 뭐야?
그럼 직장 그만두고 맨날
애인 노릇이나 해?
...so you can feel like
you have a girlfriend?
아니, 일이란 그냥
일이란 거야
It would nice if you'd realize
that it's just a job.
그냥... 일?
Just a job?
그래
It's the first time in my life
I'm doing something I care about!
내가 진정으로 좋아하는 일을
하고 있다는 거 몰라?
The first time
I'm doing something I'm good at!
내 평생 처음으로
잘 할 수 있는 걸 찾았어
- 그걸 이해할 수 없다면...
- 됐어, 이해해
If you don't get that
I get that, and I'm happy for you.
너한테 중요한 것도 알아
나도 기뻐
But I'm tired of dating your answering
machine! I don't know what to do!
하지만 꺼진 전화기에
메시지 남기는 건 지겨워
- 어째야 할지 모르겠어
- 나도 그래!
Well, neither do l!
Is this about Mark?
마크 때문이야?
Oh, my God!
맙소사!
아니군
Okay, it's not.
세상에! 난 더 이상
같은 문제로 다투기 싫어
Oh, my God!
I cannot keep having this same fight
over and over again.
자긴 우리 문제를
어렵게 만들고 있어
You're making this too hard.
내가 어렵게 만들어?
그럼 어떻게 해줄까?
I'm making this too hard?
What should I do?
나도 몰라, 모른다구!
우리 시간 좀 갖자
I don't know!
I don't know! Look...
...maybe we should just take a break!
좋아, 좋지, 그래
잠깐 쉬자, 진정하자구
Fine, you're right.
Let's take a break. Let's cool off.
시원한 콜라나 마실까?
Let's get some frozen yogurt
or something.
아니, 우리 관계 말이야
A break from us.
advances in collating
in the past five years.
5년 전에 비해
일 처리가 수월해졌죠
5천장이 들어왔다 쳐요
We just got in an X-5000, you know?
The X-5000 makes an X-50
look like a T-71.
5천장을 50장처럼 만드는
T-71이 나왔거든요
It's the dinosaur guy!
안녕! 공룡 씨!
-Hi, Ross!
-Hi, Chloe.
- 안녕, 로스
- 안녕, 클로이
I want you to meet
some friends of mine.
내 친구들 소개할게요
He's my hero. He'll want
to blow stuff up 400 percent.
여기는 나의 영웅 씨!
전에 뭔가 들고 와서
4백 배 확대해 달랬는데
그건 안 된다고 했더니
'해봐요'라고 해서
We say we don't do that. He says,
"You gotta." Know what? We did it.
우리가 해냈어요
Now anytime anybody wants 400,
we just say, "Let's Ross it!"
누구든 4백 배 확대를 원하면
이젠 "로스처럼!"하죠
And that's the only color
that comes in.
그래봐야 색은 안 바뀌잖아
Yo, Chloe! Do you have a quarter
for the condom machine?
콘돔 자판기에 쓸 동전 있어?
What are you doing? I thought
tonight's your anniversary dinner.
여긴 웬 행차야? 근사하게
기념일 축하하고 있어야지
계획이 바뀌었어, 대신
헤어지기로 했어
A little change of plans.
We're gonna break up instead.
And I can speak a little French.
저도 불어는 조금 해요
불레 부 쿠쉐 아베크 모아,
스 스와?
Why? What did I say?
왜요? 무슨 말이죠?
Well, you just asked if I wanted
to go to bed with you tonight.
오늘밤을 함께 보내자는
말인데요
Oh, my God!
이런, 모리스 카페에서
들은 말이 다 그래요
No wonder I get such great service
at Cafe Maurice.
IKnock, knock, knock.
똑똑, 똑똑!
Hi. Could you please tell Sergei
that I was fascinated...
세르게이에게 말 해줘요
신문에 난 부트로스 부트로스
갈리의 인터뷰가 좋았다구요
...by what Boutros Boutros-Ghali said
in the Times?
부트로스 부트로스
갈리라고 안 했죠?
You didn't say
"Boutros Boutros-Ghali."
Boutros Boutros-Ghali.
부트로스 부트로스 갈리
He says he was too.
같은 생각이시래요
Interesting.
잘 됐군요
- 궁금한 게 있는데...
- 두 분 대화 전에...
So I was wondering
Before you get all talky again...
세르게이에게 말 해줘요
...could you also please
tell Sergei...
옷이 참 근사하다구요
...that I really like his suit.
He said, "Thank you.
You look pretty tonight.
칭찬 고맙다고 하시고
당신도 예쁘대요
Your hair, golden like the sun."
So you're a chef?
금발머리가 태양 같대요
요리사라구요?
I'm also thinking of opening up
my own restaurant.
제 식당을 열까
생각 중이에요
그래요?
Really?
모니카, 잠깐 면담 좀 할까?
Could I talk to you
behind my menu?
What are you doing?
뭐 하는 거야?
Well, I was having a conversation.
대화를 하고 있지
미샤가 너한테 빠져서
Misha's so interested in you, Sergei
and I haven't been able to talk at all.
세르게이와 나는
두 마디 이상도 못하고 있어
You want me to sit silently,
while you three converse?
난 입다물고 셋의 대화나
지켜보라는 거야?
That would be great.
Thank you.
그게 좋겠다, 고마워
여보세요?
Hi. It's Mark.
안녕, 마크야
What? Is it my breath?
왜?
- 실망했어?
- 아니
Sorry. I just thought
you were somebody else.
미안해, 다른 사람인 줄
알았어, 안녕?
I was just gonna leave a message.
Isn't tonight your anniversary dinner?
안녕, 메시지나 남길까 했는데...
오늘 무슨 기념일이라고 했지?
그게...
Rach? Are you okay?
레이첼, 괜찮아?
괜찮아
Yeah, I'm fine.
You wanna talk?
I can come over.
얘기할까?
그리 갈까?
안돼,
아니... 난 괜찮아
Really, no. Please.
That's okay.
All right. I'm coming over
with Chinese food.
알았어, 중국 요리
사 가지고 갈게
난... 배 안 고파
I'm not hungry.
It's for me.
내가 먹으려구
그래, 이따 봐
Bye.
-So what'll you do?
-What can I do?
이제 어쩔 거야?
어쩌긴? 상대가 헤어지자면
헤어지는 거지
One person wants to break up,
you break up.
안돼, 너희는 안돼
전화해서 풀어봐
No way. This is you guys.
Call her and work it out.
We just had this huge fight.
Don't I have to wait awhile?
아주 크게 싸웠어
시간을 둬야되지 않니?
It isn't like swimming after you eat.
Pick up the phone!
식사 직후나 수영이 금물이지
당장 전화해!
You know that
swimming thing is a myth.
- 수영 얘기는 근거 없는 거야
- 알아, 레니 삼촌이 문제지
Tell that to my Uncle Lenny.
Why? What happened to him?
뭔데 그래?
삼촌은 그걸 철저히 지켜
Nothing. He just really
believes in that.
그리고 엄청나게 싸웠어
너무했어
Then we got into this big fight
It was awful.
I told him he treats me like
a park ranger, something....
도시락이 어쩌구 하면서
And then...
그리고는...
잠시 만나지 말자고 했어
... I told him
I wanted to take a break.
I don't want to take a break.
그건 진심이 아니었어
안 됐네, 계란말이 먹을래?
I'm sorry.
Egg roll?
아니
And then I called him and
he wasn't there.
아까 전화했는데, 안 받아
홧김에 나갔나봐
He's probably just out.
Thank you, that's very helpful.
I'm glad you came over.
고마워
더 걱정되게 만드는군
여보세요?
Hi, it's me.
나야
안녕
목소리 들으니 좋다
Oh, I'm so glad you called.
Really?
정말?
This is crazy. Don't you think
we can work on this?
우리가 미쳤었나봐
우리 잘 해결해보자
What do you want to drink?
마실 거 줘?
Who's that?
누구야?
Nobody?
아냐
사과주스 마셔도 돼?
Is it okay if I finish
the apple juice?
Is that Mark?
마크지?
Honey, he just came over
- 자기야... 마크가 왔어
- 그래, 알았어
Yeah, got it!
공룡 씨!
기분 나쁘면 춤이나 춰요
Hey, Dinosaur Guy!
Look at you, so sad.
Come dance.
아뇨, 됐어요
That's okay. Thanks.
웃을 필요는 없고
그냥 춤만 춰요
You don't have to smile.
You just have to dance.
춤출 기분이 아니에요
그냥 술이나 마시죠
I don't feel like dancing.
I feel like having a drink, okay?
좋아요
여기 맥주 두 병!
Two beers!
And the vet said it was time.
수의사가 때가 됐다더군요
지구 반대편에서
And so from half a world away...
...while my mother
held the phone to his ear...
어머니가 전화를 개의 귀에
대주고, 난 작별을 고했죠
... I said goodbye to my dog...
...in seven languages.
7개 국어로요
-Could I have a tissue?
-Oh, sure.
- 휴지 좀 줄래?
- 그래
I just hope you don't accidentally...
콧물 훌쩍이다
마셔버리면 곤란하지
...suck it up through your nose
and choke on it.
Sergei would like to apologize
for my behavior tonight.
세르게이 씨가 제 행동을
용서해달라고 했어요
용서해드린다고 하세요
Well, tell him, "Apology accepted."
Unbelievable. For the first time in
years, someone wants to talk to me.
미치겠군, 3년만에 처음으로
대화 상대가 나타났어요
그런데 그 꼴을 못 보고
난리라니!
But do you think he would
let me enjoy that? No!
You silly diplomat.
Why don't you learn some English?
멍청한 외교관 양반!
영어 좀 배우지 그래?
Excuse me, but isn't he paying
for your dinner?
미안하지만, 여기 식사비는
이분이 내지 않나요?
이분 개가 죽어서 그래
The man's dog just died.
I have just resigned my post.
방금 제 직위를 버렸습니다
Will you accompany me
to the Rainbow Room?
저와 함께 레인보우로
가시겠어요?
I have diplomatic coupons.
외교관 우대권이 있죠
It would be my pleasure.
기꺼이 동행하죠
My guy has coupons.
이분은 우대권이 있대
저분은 있어도 말 못하지?
Your guy can't even say "coupons."
Plate.
접시
Plate! Yes! Plate!
- 접시, 네, 접시죠
- 접시, 접시
그게 뭔 소용이죠?
See, we don't need them.
접시?
네
이 노래 좋군요
I like this song.
그럼 춤출 준비가 됐어요
Well, you're practically
dancing, already.
- 나와서 함께 춰요
- 싫어요
Why don't you just do it over here?
What are you, married?
유부남이에요?
그럼 괜찮죠
Because that's okay.
Oh, be home, be home, be home....
제발 받아, 받아, 받아
받아, 받아
집에 없어
You're not home.
Still no smile?
아직도 기분이 그래요?
다음에 계속...
Miss American Pie
Ameri-can.
아메리캔
- 아메리캔
아메리캔...
영어가 원래 어려워요
It's a very hard language.
Let's do it again.
- 천천히?
- 다시 해봐요